Aleksandr Kim

Making Aliyah to Israel on early 07/2022

■ +7(926) 476-01-50 | Maleksandr.v.kim@gmail.com | AlexVKim | Land aleksandrkim

Summary .

Experienced Data Scientist with a background in leading projects and teams, and in applying data-backed solutions to complex business issues. My journey has progressed from being an Individual Contributor to a Team Leader, and then to working in a diverse international environment. I am always focused on creating tangible customer-oriented solutions through Data Science, rather than just enhancing ML metrics.

Skills and Tools

Soft Skills Team leading, mentoring, project management, presentation skill

Python (ML/DL libs), Docker, Airflow, Git, Flask, FastAPI, Cloud computing (AWS, Databricks)

Data Mining PySpark, Hadoop, SQL, Parsing (Scrapy, Selenium, Beautiful Soup)

Data Visualization Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Bokeh etc.

Solving ML tasks NLP, Uplift-modeling, Ranking, Matching, Dynamic pricing, TS Forcasting

Analyzing Results Validation/Time Series Validation, AB Testing

> Languages English (fluent), Russian (native), Hebrew (basic), German (basic)

Work Experience

Intuit Inc. (Leading Financial Software Company)

London / Tel Aviv

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST 2022 - 2024

- Moved to London and switched to Business Data Analyst position in product team
- Delivered two models that increased error detection rate by 40%
- Developed a suite of models to automate data scraping process, projected to reduce manual workload by 50%
- Organized and led Data Science Guild, uniting machine learning professionals and enthusiasts across whole Israeli site to foster collaboration and knowledge sharing

X5 Retail Group (top Russian retailer, about 20k stores)

Moscow

TEAM LEADER IN TWO DATA SCIENCE TEAMS

2021 - 2022

- Built a production-ready ML-based promotions optimization system (new product launch + internal SLA increase)
- · Hired and leaded team of DS and DE specialists
- Organized data quality monitoring for Hive data bases

Kaspersky (international cybersecurity company)

Moscow 2019 - 2021

DATA SCIENTIST • Developed and Deployed BERT-based model for customers support automation

- (20% reduce of support costs)
- Analyzed user's behavior data, generated hypotheses and conducted AB tests to verify them (customers' Retention Rate increase)
- Developed and Deployed language identification model for customer's support (SLA increase + automation)

Raiffeisen Bank (international bank)

Moscow 2018 - 2019

• Improved local compliance scoring system (significant revenue growth)

• Developed model for customer identification (employees' workload optimization)

Digital Diesel Ltd. (diesel equipment service)

Moscow 2017 - 2018

• Analyzed market of suppliers and created model to forecast suppliers' prices

2018 - 2019

- Outsource project for an energy supplying company: overdue payments prediction model
- Hackathon "human capital convention": Best task solution award (forecast of employees dismissal)

Education

Other projects

ANALYST

MIPT (Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, leading Russian university in STEM)

Moscow 2016 - 2018

MASTER'S DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

• Thesis: Distributed Support Vector Machines with Privileged Information

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2012 - 2016

Thesis: Research of Quadratic Mappings. Building a Border of Image Set of Non Convex Functions